Guide to the Rob Amberg photographs and papers, 1975-2009 and undated RL.00031
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series, 1976-2008 and undated, 6 boxes
  - Books and Journals, 1996-2008
    - Brunk, Robert S., ed., May We All Remember Well: A Journal of the History & Cultures of Western North Carolina 1. Asheville, NC: Robert S. Brunk Auction Services Inc., 1997. (Box 28)
    - Chalker, Donald M., ed., Leadership for Rural Schools: Lessons for All Educators. Lancaster, PA: Technomic Publishing Co., 1999. (Box 28)
    - The Georgia Review: Contemporary Southern Writing L, no. 1 (Spring 1996). (Box 28)
    - Hulme, Francis Pledger, Mountain Measure: A Southern Appalachian Verse Notebook. Boone, NC: Appalachian Consortium Press, 1975. (Box 28)
    - Road Scholars Speakers Bureau 2007/2008 Catalog: A Program of the North Carolina Humanities Council. (Box 28)
    - Southern Cultuers: Soil, Sand, and States of Mind 7, no.3 (Fall 2001). (Box 29)
    - The Southern Quarterly 35, no. 3 (Spring 1997). (Box 29)
- Subject Files Series, 1987-2002 and undated, 2 boxes
  Series consists of non-profit organizations with which Amberg worked and supported. Series described at the folder level.
  - Mary Reynolds Babcock Foundation, 1995-2002 (Box 23)
  - Carolina Community Project, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Community Farm Alliance, undated (Box 23)
  - Community Foundation of Western North Carolina, 1994-1998 (Box 23)
  - Moses Cone-Wesley Long Community Health Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 23)
  - Environmental Defense Fund, 1994 (Box 23)
  - Farm Aid (Box 23)
  - The Ford Foundation, 1994 (Box 23)
  - International Forum on Globalization, 1998 (Box 23)
  - Madison County Arts Council, undated (Box 23)
  - North Carolina Arts Council, 1994-1999 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina Humanities Council (Box 24)
  - Pesticide Action Network, 1994 (Box 24)
  - Pew Partnership for Civic Change, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Rural Advancement Foundation International (RAFI-USA) (Box 24)
  - Rural Center, 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Rural School and Community Trust, undated (Box 24)
  - SAREACE Southern Region, 1994 and undated (Box 24)
  - Southern Appalachian Center of Mars Hill College, undated (Box 24)
  - United Farmers Organization (Box 24)
- Writings and Research Series, 1990s-2008 and undated, 5 boxes
  Series includes multiple manuscripts to The New Road and Sodom Laurel Album in addition to Amberg's notes and other writings.
  - The New Road book contract and donor list (Box 25)
  - From Kalamazoo to Jasper and Home Again (Box 25)
  - I-26 Research (Box 25)
  - Interviews and related notes (Box 25)
  - Maps (Box 25)
  - The New Road manuscript, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - The New Road introduction draft (Box 25)
  - The New Road final chapter draft (Box 25)
  - The New Road publisher's draft, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - Sodom Laurel Album manuscript, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album annotated draft (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album draft (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album layout draft (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album book permissions (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album book cover (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album publisher's draft, 4 of 7 folders (Box 26)
  - Sodom Laurel Album publisher's draft, 3 of 7 folders (Box 27)
  - The New Road full publisher's draft, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Sodom Laurel Album publisher's drafts, 2 copies (Box 30)
  - The New Road publisher's drafts, 2 copies (Box 31)
  - Quartet: Four North Carolina Photographers publisher's draft (Box 32)
  - Oversize Writings
    - Beyond Black and White, 2002 (Box 32)
    - Corridor of Change, undated (Box 32)
    - Diary of a French Broad, 1978 (Box 32)
    - Tobacco: An Interview with Dellie Norton, 1997 (Box 32)
  - The New Road book cover (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Oversize promotional posters (Oversize-folder 1)
- Audio Series, 1997-2001, 1 box
  Interstate 26 is a cassette recording while the Sodom Laurel Album accompanying recording is in a compact disc format.
  - Interstate 26 produced by Leda Hartman, 1997 Sept. 22 (Box 29)
  - Sodom Laurel Album accompanying recording (Box 29)